

Andrash Yang

Full-Stack Web Developer

Nationality: Taiwanese
Fluent in English / Native Mandarin speaker

My Portfolio:

https://andrash.dev/

My GitHub:

https://github.com/cocoychris

I am a **senior software developer** who has been coding for over a **decade**. I started out as an indie game and mobile app developer, and in recent (4+) years have transitioned to **full-stack web development**, specializing in **Node.js**, **React**, and **TypeScript**.

Software development has always been a passion of mine. It started as a hobby when I was little and turned into a career that I really enjoy. I see my code as my baby and am always looking for a way to make it better.

This is why I care about the structure and maintainability of a codebase, because I know from past experience how painful and difficult it can be to expand a codebase that is built in a poor way.

I am comfortable working on a project from start to finish alone or with a small team.

I'm looking for a **fully remote** role in a collaborative, creative environment where I can use my skills to create more.

Full-Stack Skill Set

Backend **Frontend Auth & Security** • TypeScript (8/10) React.js (7/10) Passport.js Node.js (9/10) Cookie-based session JQuery Nest.js (7/10) or without JWT implementation RWD using CSS Express.js (8/10) CORS setup Material UI REST API design Vite (Webpack replacement) **CSRF** prevention Socket.io **SVG** Animation Password encryption SSR with EJS Zod data validation Database **Dev & Deployment Tools Others** OOP design pattern (8/10) Database design and Docker (6/10) operation using: Swagger, JSDoc and SOA design pattern PostgreSQL TypeDoc Web scraping with Puppeteer Prisma ORM Custom algorithm for games o Drizzle ORM Jest unit testing & business logic • Git & GitHub

Featured Full-Stack Projects



HiGo Shared Electric Scooter (Latest Project)

I developed a robust **backend system** for a shared electric scooter rental service located in Kaohsiung City, Taiwan. Implemented core functionality, business logic, and REST APIs to power both **mobile apps** (<u>Android, iOS</u>) and **management portal** (private website). Key features included vehicle management, user authentication, payment processing, and real-time location tracking.



Playground by Andrash:

A Gamified Portfolio

This website reimagines the portfolio experience with a unique, game-like twist. Users engage in a **real-time multiplayer world**, built from scratch using Socket.io. Invite friends and explore together as your character avatars move in sync! The game **rendering relies on React.js**, showcasing its power without external engines. But the fun doesn't stop there; a **built-in map editor** allows users to create their own custom worlds.

Learn More

- The website: https://andrash.dev/
- Introduction Article:
 https://andrash.dev/page/md/about_this_place



Automated Robot Platform

I developed a robust Robotic Process Automation (RPA) system to automate repetitive tasks. This platform includes a **web interface for managing and monitoring bot processes**, enabling scheduling, queuing, and real-time tracking. Additionally, a powerful **scripting API** empowers bot builders to automate complex actions across web and desktop applications. These actions include SFTP operations, email interactions, file downloads, and simulated keyboard input.

Learn More

- Demo Video on YouTube: https://youtu.be/IO3-2 hz4XU
- Introduction Article:
 https://andrash.dev/page/md/project_arp_system
 m

Education

Earned a bachelor's degree in philosophy from Chinese Culture University, graduating early with honors in 2012. Self-taught in programming and web development since 2003 while in high school, motivated by the dream of making my own computer game (with Macromedia/Adobe Flash).

Work Experience



Backend Developer
Handy Tech Ltd. (Cambrian soft)
08/2024 - Now
Tainan, Taiwan

 Worked on the HiGo Shared Electric Scooter project as the primary backend developer, responsible for implementing the core feature, business logic, database schema, REST API, Swagger documentation and project deployment.



Information System Senior Executive BRAND'S SUNTORY LTD. TAIWAN BRANCH (MALAYSIA) 08/2019 - 02/2023 Taipei, Taiwan

- Worked on the ARP (Automated Robot Platform) system as the primary designer & full-stack developer.
- Managed the CEM & SAP systems. Performed data monitoring & synchronization between these systems using the ARP system.



Mobile App Engineer
QLL (Quick Language Learning) Pte.
Ltd
01/2015 - 02/2016

- Developed 3+ cross-platform mobile apps using Corona SDK (Solar 2D) and Lua. Responsible for building the company's core product (QLand App, an interactive ebook reader for language learning) as the primary developer.
- Built a UI component library and an OOP library that turns Lua into an OOP language.
- Learn more: https://andrash.dev/page/md/mobile_app_dev



Computer Science & Coding Teacher (Part-time)

Qing Shui High School

 Taught computer science and coding (HTML, Lua, etc...) to high school students.



Mobile App Engineer Intern
QLL (Quick Language Learning) Pte.
Ltd
04/2012 - 02/2013

04/2012 - 02/2013 Taipei, Taiwan

Taipei, Taiwan

- Became familiar with the Corona SDK (Solar 2D) and Lua.
- Developed FBDraw, a painting app that comes with different brushes and allows users to post their paintings to their Facebook.



Indie game developer Freelance / Non-profit 09/2008 - 04/2012 Taipei, Taiwan

- Created Flash games as a hobby and offered them for free while studying philosophy in college.
- Also worked as a freelance software developer for a few months, collaborating with my philosophy professor to create interactive software as the teaching material for his logic class.
- My game projects:
 https://andrash.dev/page/md/indie_game_development

- Start coding & learning since 2003 -